We've all been there – staring at a pile of books, desperately hoping that what we study will stick in our mind.
我们都有过这样的经历——盯着一堆书，迫切地希望自己学的内容能牢牢记在脑子里。
Many of us have probably asked if there's any way that we can get better at remembering things.
很多人可能都问过，有没有什么方法能让我们的记忆力变得更好？
So, why don't we look at what memory experts say about this?
那么，我们不妨来看看记忆专家是怎么说的。
Every student who has made flashcards knows that it can be helpful to go back over what they've studied before.
每个做过抽认卡的学生都知道，复习之前学过的内容是很有帮助的。
According to The Learning Scientists – a group of cognitive scientists – we can learn things better if we wait for some time before trying to study them again.
认知科学家团队“学习科学家”指出，如果我们间隔一段时间再去复习所学内容，学习效果会更好。
They say that trying to retrieve something from your memory after you have had some time to forget it will make it easier to remember in future.
他们表示，在经过一段时间、有些内容快要遗忘时，尝试从记忆中提取这些信息，会让它们在未来更容易被记起。
Similarly, David Robson, writing for BBC Future, highlights studies that show taking some time to just do nothing after studying might mean that you can remember things better afterwards.
无独有偶，为BBC未来频道撰稿的大卫·罗布森强调，有研究表明，学习后花点时间什么都不做，可能会让你之后的记忆力变得更好。
We don't know exactly why this happens, but it has been suggested that it's to do with the relationship between long-term and short-term memory.
我们目前还不完全清楚背后的原因，但有观点认为，这与长时记忆和短时记忆之间的关联有关。
Another study tip from The Learning Scientists is to change between different topics as you study.
“学习科学家”团队还给出了另一个学习技巧：学习时穿插不同的主题。
They say this can help you build links between different ideas.
他们认为，这样做有助于在不同的知识点之间建立联系。
Now, linking ideas and relating them to each other or to images are often suggested as good ways to memorise something.
而将知识点相互关联，或是把它们和具体图像联系起来，向来都被视为有效的记忆方法。
Former world memory champion Jonathan Hancock highlights how picturing pieces of information in different physical locations or linking them to memorable images makes them easier to remember.
前世界记忆冠军乔纳森·汉考克强调，把信息片段想象成储存在不同的具体位置，或是将其与容易记住的图像绑定，都能让记忆变得更轻松。
Linking new information to things that are easier to remember is a technique that many people use – it could be making letter patterns into words called mnemonics, or by sorting things into categories.
将新信息与更容易记住的事物关联起来，是很多人都会用的技巧——比如把字母组合转化成单词的记忆术，或是将信息分门别类。
There are also more general things that we can do to improve our memory.
此外，还有一些更通用的方法可以提升记忆力。
Hancock says that being generally organised makes things easier for your brain, while many other experts also recommend avoiding stress, alcohol and smoking, and that we should get a lot of rest and exercise.
汉考克表示，保持生活条理清晰，能让大脑的运转更轻松。其他许多专家也建议，要避免压力过大，远离酒精和烟草，同时保证充足的休息和适量的运动。
So, the good news to take from this is that while it may be hard, improving our memory is something we can control.
所以，我们可以从中得到一个好消息：提升记忆力虽然并非易事，但它是一件我们能够掌控的事情。